{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question_id": 1,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "The population of City X increased from 2 million in the year 2000 to 2.5 million in 2015 and the gross domestic product of the city in 2000 was 3/8 less than that in 2015. What was the approximate percent change, rounded to the nearest integer if required, in the per capita gross domestic product of the city from 2000 to 2015?",
      "options": {
        "A": "22% decrease",
        "B": "22% increase",
        "C": "28% increase",
        "D": "53% increase",
        "E": "113% increase."
      },
      "correct_answer": "C",
      "difficulty": "Challenging"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 4,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "Company X sold 1,500 units of its product for $9 each and 750 units for $6 each. If the company's cost of producing each unit of the product was $7, what was the company's profit or loss on the sale of 2,250 units?",
      "options": {
        "A": "$2,250 loss",
        "B": "$750 loss",
        "C": "No profit or loss",
        "D": "$2,250 profit",
        "E": "$18,000 profit"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Easy"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 47,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "Three vessels A, B, and C of capacity 120 litres each contain a mixture of alcohol and spirit. Vessel A contains 100 litres of the mixture with 65% alcohol. Vessel B has 70% alcohol and this vessel is half empty. The vessel C has 80 litres of mixture out of which 20 litres are spirit. Now, the mixture from vessel A is poured into vessel B until vessel B is completely filled. Then the mixture from vessel B is poured into vessel C until C is completely filled. Now the entire mixture from vessel C is poured into the vessels A and B. What is the ratio of alcohol in vessels A and B?",
      "options": {
        "A": "4/5",
        "B": "9/10",
        "C": "84/83",
        "D": "28/27",
        "E": "23/22"
      },
      "correct_answer": "C",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 60,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "A solution contains ethanol, methanol and water in the ratio of 1:4:15 by volume. The composition of this solution is altered by adding ethanol, methanol and water such that the amount of ethanol per unit volume of methanol increases by 15 percentage points and the amount of water per unit volume of ethanol decreases by two-thirds. If the volume of the altered solution is 340 cubic units, which of the following is the volume, in cubic units, of methanol in the altered solution?",
      "options": {
        "A": "20",
        "B": "40",
        "C": "50",
        "D": "100",
        "E": "200"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 61,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "Mark owns four low-quality watches. Watch1 loses 15 minutes every hour. Watch2 gains 15 minutes every hour relative to watch1 (that is, as watch1 moves from 12:00 to 1:00, watch2 moves from 12:00 to 1:15). Watch3 loses 20 minutes every hour relative to watch2. Finally, watch4 gains 20 minutes every hour relative to watch3. If Mark resets all four watches to the correct time at 12 noon, what time will watch4 show at 12 midnight that day?",
      "options": {
        "A": "10:00",
        "B": "10:34",
        "C": "11:02",
        "D": "11:48",
        "E": "12:20"
      },
      "correct_answer": "A",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 63,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "A farmer has decided to build a wire fence along one straight side of his property. For this, he planned to place several fence posts at 6 m intervals, with posts fixed at both ends of the side. After he bought the posts and wire, he found that the number of posts he had bought was 5 less than required. However, he discovered that the number of posts he had bought would be just sufficient if he spaced them 8 m apart. What is the length of the side of his property and how many posts did he buy?",
      "options": {
        "A": "100 m, 15",
        "B": "100 m, 16",
        "C": "120 m, 15",
        "D": "120 m, 16",
        "E": "130 m, 16"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 79,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "Ben’s music album sold 5/6 the number of copies as Regina’s album. If Regina’s album sold at least 1,500 copies more than Ben’s album, how many copies of Ben’s album were sold?",
      "options": {
        "A": "I only",
        "B": "II only",
        "C": "III only",
        "D": "I and III only",
        "E": "I, II and III"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 81,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "A certain square is to be drawn on a coordinate plane. One of the vertices must be on the origin, and the square is to have an area of 100. If all coordinates of the vertices must be integers, how many different ways can this square be drawn?",
      "options": {
        "A": "4",
        "B": "6",
        "C": "8",
        "D": "10",
        "E": "12"
      },
      "correct_answer": "E",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 84,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "In a game, one player throws two fair, six-sided die at the same time. If the player receives at least a five or a one on either die, that player wins. What is the probability that a player wins after playing the game once?",
      "options": {
        "A": "1/3",
        "B": "4/9",
        "C": "5/9",
        "D": "2/3",
        "E": "3/4"
      },
      "correct_answer": "C",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 93,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "Edward and Klara are both nurses who are good friends with each other. Edward works at Brigade Hospital, where, in every 10 day cycle, he works the first 7 days and has three days off. Klara works at Cedar Mountain Hospital, where, in every 7 day cycle, she works the first 5 days, and has 2 days off. Assume that both start their respective cycles on Day 1 of Week 1. In which weeks do they have the same two days off?",
      "options": {
        "A": "I only",
        "B": "II only",
        "C": "III only",
        "D": "I and III only",
        "E": "I, II and III"
      },
      "correct_answer": "D",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 100,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "In a 1000-mile race Flash gives Superman a head start of 40 miles and beats him by 19 milliseconds. If, in a 1000-mile race, Flash gives Superman a head start of 30 milliseconds then Superman beats Flash by 40 miles. What is the ratio of speed of Flash to that of Superman?",
      "options": {
        "A": "4:5",
        "B": "5:6",
        "C": "6:5",
        "D": "5:4",
        "E": "4:3"
      },
      "correct_answer": "C",
      "difficulty": "Hard"
    },
    {
      "question_id": 101,
      "section": "Quantitative Reasoning",
      "subtype": "Problem Solving",
      "subtype-type": "Word Problem",
      "question": "A square in the coordinate plane has vertices whose y-coordinates are 0, 1, 4, and 5. What is the area of the square?",
      "options": {
        "A": "16",
        "B": "17",
        "C": "25",
        "D": "26",
        "E": "27"
      },
      "correct_answer": "B",
      "difficulty": "Medium"
    }
  ]
}